A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, President, Frederick Seitz FA1069
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University records, President, Frederick Seitz
1932-1998
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University.
Seitz, Frederick
FA1069
152.4 Cubic Feet
127 record storage cartons.
Conditions Governing Access note
Records more than 25 years old are open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
When requesting to view audiovisual material, please refer to the Title and the AV Number (example: AV 1916). Researchers are asked to check the "Restrictions" note for each Title. If a Title does not currently have an access copy, please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 304-U
Arrangement
Records remain arranged as received.
Other Finding Aids
For other Seitz materials currently open for research see:
FA141 Rockefeller University records, President, Frederick Seitz, Business, Series 1.
FA815 Rockefeller University records, President, Frederick Seitz, Chronological Files, Series 2.
FA816 Rockefeller University records, President, Frederick Seitz, Archive Center, Series 3.
FA817 Rockefeller University records, President, Frederick Seitz, Campus, Series 4.
FA818 Rockefeller University records, President, Frederick Seitz, General Administration, Series 5.
FA819 Rockefeller University records, President, Frederick Seitz, Personal, Biographical and Miscellaneous, Series 6.
Biographical / Historical
Frederick Seitz (b. July 4, 1911, d. March 2, 2008) was a physicist and science administrator. He has made fundamental contributions to the theory of solids, nuclear physics, fluorescence, and crystals, and has been a leader in the post - World War II scientific establishment in the United States. From 1968-1978 Seitz was president of the Rockefeller University.
Seitz entered Stanford University in January 1929, where he started out as a biochemistry major, but soon focused on mathematics and physics. He graduated from Stanford in three years with a degree in mathematics, and started doctoral studies in physics at Princeton University at the beginning of 1932. Completing his doctorate in 1934 Seitz remained at Princeton as a Proctor Fellow, and in 1935 was appointed as an instructor at the University of Rochester. In 1939 Seitz moved to the University of Pennsylvania first as assistant professor, 1939-1941, and then associate professor, 1941-1942, in the Morgan Laboratory of Physics. Seitz moved to the University of Illinois in 1949 to accept an appointment as a professor of Physics. In the 40s and 50s Seitz's research focused on the properties of crystals. His published works included studies of dislocations and imperfections in crystal structures, the effect of irradiation on crystals, and the process of diffusion in crystalline materials. In 1962 Seitz was elected president of the National Academy of Sciences in Washington, a position which he held for 6 years. In that same year, he became a trustee of the Rockefeller University and in 1968 he went on to become president of the Rockefeller University. In 1973 he received the National Medal of Science, the nation's highest award in science, for his contributions "to the foundation of the modern quantum theory of the solid state of matter."
Among his numerous honors and awards, Dr. Seitz received the Franklin Medal in 1965, the Herbert Hoover Medal in 1968, the Defense Department Distinguished Service Award in Awards in 1968, the NASA distinguished Service in 1969, the Compton Award, the highest award of the American Institute of Physics, in 1970, and the James Madison Medal of Princeton University in 1978. In 1979 he received his second NASA Distinguished Public Service Medal presented for his "dedicated service as chairman of the NASA Space Program Advisory Council from 1973 to 1977. " In addition to the Rockefeller University, 26 universities in this country and abroad have awarded him honorary degrees. In 1983 he received the Fourth Vannevar Bush Award presented by the National Science Board of the National Science Foundation and the R. Loveland Memorial Award of the American College of Physicians. From 1978 to 1983 he served as vice chairman of the Board of Trustees of the Memorial Sloan - Kettering Cancer Center.
Other memberships include the American Academy of Arts and Sciences, The Century Club, the Bohemian Club, the American Philosophical Society, the American Society for Metals, the American Institute of Mining, Metallurgy and Petroleum Engineers, the American Crystallographic Society, the Optical Society of America, the Washington Academy of Science, and a number of European scientific academies.
- Chronological Correspondence, 1978 July-1980 (Box 1, Folder 1-24)
- Chronological Correspondence, 1981-1983 (Box 2, Folder 1-29)
- Chronological Correspondence, 1984-1986 (Box 3, Folder 1-30)
- Chronological Correspondence, 1987-1989 (Box 4, Folder 1-30)
- Chronological Correspondence, 1990-1992 (Box 5, Folder 1-36)
- Chronological Correspondence, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 1-6)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted - Open in 2019.
- Chronological Correspondence, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 1-6)
  Restricted - Open in 2020.
- Weekly Appointment Calendars, 1979-1983 (Box 8)
- Weekly Appointment Calendars, 1984-1989 (Box 9)
- Ogden Corporation, 1977-1981 (Box 10, Folder 1-11)
  Scope and Contents
  Board of Directors files, Operations, Management Committee and Technology Committee files as well as associated subcomittee and Trip files.
- Ogden Corporation, 1981-1987 (Box 11, Folder 1-14)
- Ogden Corporation, 1988-1992 (Box 12, Folder 1-9)
- Ogden Corporation, 1993-1998 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  Restricted - Open in 2024.
- Republic of China (Taiwan) - Board of Advisors, 1979-1981 (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Republic of China (Taiwan) - National Science Council, 1983-1988 (Box 12, Folder 12)
- Whitney Symposia on Science and Technology (General Electric), 1985 (Box 12, Folder 13)
- National Accelerator Laboratory, 1973-1975 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA), 1975-1981 (Box 13, Folder 2-5)
- NASA - Space Program Advisory Council (SPAC), 1967-1975 (Box 13, Folder 6-14)
- Committee for Nomination of NASA Chief Scientist, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 15)
- Space Shuttle Program, 1971-1973 (Box 13, Folder 16)
- National Bureau of Standards, 1972-1987 (Box 14, Folder 1)
- National Commission on Materials Policy, 1971-1973 (Box 14, Folder 2-4)
- National Council on Radiation Protection and Measurements, 1970-1991 (Box 14, Folder 5-14)
- National Security Industrial Association, 1968-1969 (Box 15, Folder 1)
- National Selective Service Scientific Advisory Group, 1969-1970 (Box 15, Folder 2)
- National Space Society, 1991 (Box 15, Folder 3)
- National Science Foundation, 1969-1991 (Box 15, Folder 4-14)
  Files include but are not limited to: MIT Site Visit Panel; High Magnetic Field Panel; Vannevar Bush Award given to Seitz; Seitz Site Visit to the Battelle; the Waterman Awards; and the Ultrasonic Imaging Task Force.
- National Science Foundation - National Medal of Science - President's Committee on the National Medal of Science, 1969-1986 (Box 16, Folder 1)
- National Science Foundation - National Medal of Science - Overhauser, 1979-1991 (Box 16, Folder 2)
- National Science Foundation - Survey of Scientific Cooperation with Developing Countries, 1976-1979 (Box 16, Folder 3)
- National Strategy Information Center, 1970-1991 (Box 16, Folder 4-6)
- North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) - The Next Thirty Years, Brussels, 1979 September 1-3 (Box 16, Folder 7)
- North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) - Science Committee, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 8-9)
- North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO), 1985-1989 (Box 16, Folder 10-11)
- Naval Research Advisory Committee (NRAC), 1969-1972 (Box 16, Folder 12-13)
- Naval Applied Science Laboratory, Brooklyn, NY, 1968-1969 (Box 16, Folder 14)
- Naval Research Laboratory, 1969-1983 (Box 16, Folder 15)
- New York Academy of Sciences, 1970-1992 (Box 17, Folder 1-2)
- New York Institute of Ocean Resources, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 3)
- Nutrition Foundation, 1976-1986 (Box 17, Folder 4-17)
- Nutrition Foundation, 1970-1976 (Box 18, Folder 1-4)
- McGraw Hill, Encyclopedia - Science and Technology, 1969-1986 (Box 18, Folder 5-6)
- Manhattan Institute, The Roundtable, 1992 (Box 18, Folder 7)
- Manpower Institute, 1970-1979 (Box 18, Folder 8-9)
- Marine Biomedical Institute, 1972-1985 (Box 18, Folder 10-13)
- Marposs Guages Inc., 1984-1990 (Box 18, Folder 14)
- Mayor's Commission for Science and Technology of the City of New York, 1984-1988 (Box 19, Folder 1)
- Memorial Sloan-Kettering Cancer Center (MSKCC), 1981-1992 (Box 19, Folder 2-12)
- Merrill Lynch - Scientific Advisory Board, 1984-1987 (Box 19, Folder 13)
- Merill Lynch - Tech Ventures, 1987-1988 (Box 19, Folder 14)
- Michelson-Morley Award Committee, 1969 (Box 19, Folder 15)
- Monnell Chemical Senses Center, 1972-1988 (Box 19, Folder 16)
- National Academy of Engineering, 1968-1991 (Box 20, Folder 1)
- National Academy of Sciences (NAS) - General, 1980-1990 (Box 20, Folder 2-11)
- National Academy of Sciences (NAS) - Commission on Peace and National Security, 1973 (Box 20, Folder 12)
- National Academy of Sciences (NAS) - Council, 1974-1986 (Box 20, Folder 13-16)
- National Academy of Sciences (NAS) - History, 1969-1973 (Box 21, Folder 1)
- National Academy of Sciences (NAS) - Development Drive, 1982-1983 (Box 21, Folder 2-3)
- National Academy of Sciences (NAS) - Development Committee, 1984 (Box 21, Folder 4)
- National Academy of Sciences (NAS) - Resource and Development, 1984-1989 (Box 21, Folder 5-6)
- National Academy of Sciences (NAS) - Dryden Memorial Fund, 1971-1972 (Box 21, Folder 7)
- National Academy of Sciences (NAS) - Board on Science and Technology for International Development (BOSTID), 1978-1988 (Box 21, Folder 8-17)
- National Academy of Sciences (NAS) - Finance Committee, 1980-1992 (Box 22, Folder 1-7)
- National Academy of Sciences (NAS) - Peace Corps Report, 1974 (Box 22, Folder 8)
- National Academy of Sciences (NAS) - Proceedings, 1986-1990 (Box 22, Folder 9)
- National Academy of Sciences (NAS) - Committees and Studies, 1969-1988 (Box 22, Folder 10-11)
- National Academy of Sciences (NAS) - Public Welfare Medal, 1971-1974 (Box 22, Folder 12)
- National Academy of Sciences (NAS) - Space Science Board, 1973-1976 (Box 22, Folder 13-15)
- National Academy of Sciences (NAS) - National Research Council-Solid State Sciences Panel, 1969-1972 (Box 22, Folder 16)
- National Academy of Sciences (NAS) - USSR Academy of Sciences, 1972 November 1-5 (Box 22, Folder 17)
- National Academy of Sciences (NAS) - US-USSR Symposium, 1970 January 7-14 (Box 22, Folder 18)
- National Academy of Sciences (NAS) - National Research Council (NRC) - General, 1979-1991 (Box 23, Folder 1)
- National Academy of Sciences (NAS) - National Research Council (NRC) - A-Bomb Dosimetry Panel, 1982-1989 (Box 23, Folder 2-10)
- National Academy of Sciences (NAS) - National Research Council (NRC) - Committee on Research Grants, 1983-1989 (Box 23, Folder 11-16)
- National Academy of Sciences (NAS) - National Research Council (NRC) - Committee on Research Grants - BOSTID, 1981-1983 (Box 24, Folder 1-3)
- National Academy of Sciences (NAS) - National Research Council (NRC) - Commission on International Relations, 1981-1982 (Box 24, Folder 4)
- National Academy of Sciences (NAS) - National Research Council (NRC) - Large International Facilities for Science and Technology, 1984-1988 (Box 24, Folder 5-6)
- National Academy of Sciences (NAS) - National Research Council (NRC) - Major Materials Facilities Committee, 1983-1989 (Box 24, Folder 7-9)
- National Academy of Sciences (NAS) - National Research Council (NRC) - US Civil Aviation Manufacturing Industry Panel, 1982-1985 (Box 24, Folder 10-11)
- Rothenberg, 1984-1986 (Box 24, Folder 12)
- The Roundtable Club (Box 24, Folder 13)
- Royal Society of Arts, London, New York, 1974-1991 (Box 24, Folder 14)
- Royal Society of South Africa, 1990 (Box 24, Folder 15)
- Science and Engineering Committee for a Secure World, 1986-1990 (Box 24, Folder 16)
- Science and Environmental Policy Project, 1992 (Box 24, Folder 17)
- Scientists and Engineers for Secure Energy, Inc., 1983-1992 (Box 25, Folder 1-14)
- Scientists and Engineers for Secure Energy, Inc., 1981-1983, 1986 (Box 26, Folder 1-8)
- Research Corporation, 1983-1992 (Box 26, Folder 9-11)
- Science and Technology Reagan Task Force Transition Team, 1980-1982 (Box 26, Folder 12-13)
- Scientists for a Strong Energy Program, 1975 (Box 26, Folder 14)
- South Africa, 1989 (Box 26, Folder 15)
- Southwest Center for Advanced Studies, 1969 (Box 27, Folder 1)
- Space Science Board, 1975-1976 (Box 27, Folder 2)
- Springer-Verlag, 1990-1992 (Box 27, Folder 3)
- Stanford Research Institute, 1969-1976 (Box 27, Folder 4)
- Stanford University, 1971-1991 (Box 27, Folder 5)
- Superconducting Supercollider, 1987 (Box 27, Folder 6)
- Technology in Society - Requests for Articles, 1985-1986 (Box 27, Folder 7-9)
- Texas College and Universitites Systems, Coordinating Board, 1985-1989 (Box 27, Folder 10-13)
- Strategic Defense Initiative (SDI), 1984-1987 (Box 27, Folder 14-21)
- Strategic Defense Initiative (SDI), 1987-1992 (Box 28, Folder 1-7)
- Scientists Institute for Public Information (SIPI), 1980-1990 (Box 28, Folder 8-12)
- Solar Energy Research Institute (SERI) Committee, 1975-1976 (Box 28, Folder 13)
- Sherman-Fairchild Foundation, 1983-1990 (Box 28, Folder 14)
- Sigma Xi (Box 28, Folder 15-16)
- Sloan Commission on Cable Communications, 1970-1972 (Box 28, Folder 17)
- Smithsonian Institution, 1969-1992 (Box 29, Folder 1)
- Teller Foundation - Teller Tribute Dinner, 1991-1992 (Box 29, Folder 2)
- Texas Instruments Foundation, 1982-1990 (Box 29, Folder 3-4)
- UNESCO, 1984-1990 (Box 29, Folder 5-9)
- United States Information Agency (USIA), 1984 (Box 29, Folder 10)
- United States Information Agency (USIA) - Yellow Rain, 1983-1984 (Box 29, Folder 11)
- University Centers for Rational Alternatives, 1971-1991 (Box 29, Folder 12)
- University Corporation for Atmospheric Research (UCAR), 1981-1988 (Box 29, Folder 13-14)
- University of Dallas, Haggerty Dedication, 1985 March 25-30 (Box 29, Folder 15)
- University of Illinois, 1969-1991 (Box 29, Folder 16-17)
- University of Illinois - Wheeler Loomis Lab Dedication, 1980 February 14 (Box 29, Folder 18)
- University of Illinois - Seitz Lab Dedication, 1993 (Box 29, Folder 19)
- University of Illinois - Beckman Institute, 1986-1992 (Box 29, Folder 20-21)
- University of Miami - School of Engineering and Architecture, 1982-1989 (Box 29, Folder 22-23)
- University of Miami - School of Engineering and Architecture, 1984-1989 (Box 30, Folder 1)
- University of Pennsylvania - Natural Science Association Advisory Board, 1985-1991 (Box 30, Folder 2-3)
- University of Pennsylvania - School of Medicine Res. Review Committee, 1986 (Box 30, Folder 4)
- University of Pennsylvania - Honorary Degree, 1985-1987 (Box 30, Folder 5)
- University of Port Elizabeth, 1978-1991 (Box 30, Folder 6)
- University of Rochester, 1984-1985 (Box 30, Folder 7)
- University of Texas, Pan American, 1991-1993 (Box 30, Folder 8)
- University of Toronto, 1990 (Box 30, Folder 9)
- United Nations Conference on Science and Technology, 1975-1979 (Box 30, Folder 10-11)
- Washington Center for Metropolitan Centers, 1969-1974 (Box 30, Folder 12)
- Washington University, St. Louis - Bontanical Garden Steering Committee (Box 30, Folder 13)
- Weizmann Institute, 1992 (Box 30, Folder 14)
- Wenner-Gren Foundation for Anthropological Research, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 15)
- The White House - Sonunu, Bromley, Quayle (Box 30, Folder 16)
- The White House, Executive Office of the President - President Science and Advisory Committee (PSAC), 1969-1977 (Box 30, Folder 17)
- The White House, Executive Office of the President, Office of Science and Technology, 1969-1983 (Box 30, Folder 18)
- Wolf Foundation, 1983-1990 (Box 30, Folder 19)
- Woodrow Wilson National Fellowship Foundation (WWNFF), 1983-1990 (Box 30, Folder 20-22)
- Woodrow Wilson National Fellowship Foundation (WWNFF), 1980-1982 (Box 31, Folder 1-7)
- Woods Hole Marine Biological Laboratory, 1970 (Box 31, Folder 8)
- Woods Hole - General, 1969-1974 (Box 31, Folder 9-10)
- World Academy of Arts and Science, 1969-1985 (Box 31, Folder 11)
- R. J. Reynolds - Foreign Grants, 1977-1979 (Box 31, Folder 12)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - General, 1978-1979 (Box 31, Folder 13-14)
- R. J. Reynolds - Dr. James Shannon, 1978-1985 (Box 31, Folder 15-16)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - General, 1980 (Box 31, Folder 17-18)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - General, 1981-1982 (Box 32, Folder 1-5)
- R. J. Reynolds - Proposals, 1979-1981 (Box 32, Folder 6-7)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - General, 1981-1983 (Box 32, Folder 8-10)
- R. J. Reynolds - Proposals, 1984 (Box 32, Folder 11)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - General, 1984-1985 (Box 32, Folder 12-13)
- R. J. Reynolds - Proposals, 1985-1986 (Box 32, Folder 14-15)
- R. J. Reynolds - Review of Medical Research Program, 1985-1986 (Box 32, Folder 16)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - General, 1986 (Box 33, Folder 1)
- R. J. Reynolds - Nabisco Medical Research Committee, 1979-1987 (Box 33, Folder 2)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - General, 1987 (Box 33, Folder 3-4)
- R. J. Reynolds - Proposals, 1987 (Box 33, Folder 5)
- R. J. Reynolds - John Bacon, 1980-1986 (Box 33, Folder 6-7)
- R. J. Reynolds - H. C. Boemer, 1981-1986 (Box 33, Folder 8)
- R. J. Reynolds - McCarty, 1978-1989 (Box 33, Folder 9)
- R. J. Reynolds - Research Scholar Awards, 1986-1988 (Box 33, Folder 10)
- R. J. Reynolds - Grant Budgets (Box 33, Folder 11)
- R. J. Reynolds - Proposals, 1988 (Box 33, Folder 12)
- R. J. Reynolds - Medical Research Committee, 1988 (Box 33, Folder 13)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - General, 1979-1989 (Box 33, Folder 14)
- R. J. Reynolds - Walter O. Spitzer Study of Passive Smoking, 1987-1990 (Box 33, Folder 15-16)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - General, 1988-1989 (Box 33, Folder 17-18)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - Grant Files - Boston University - Paul H. Black, 1988 (Box 34, Folder 1)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - Grant Files - Bowan Gray - Stephen B. Mizel, 1986-1988 (Box 34, Folder 2)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - Grant Files - Bowman Gray - Buckalew, 1982-1987 (Box 34, Folder 3-6)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - Grant Files - Bowman Gray - Clarkson, 1979-1983 (Box 34, Folder 7-11)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - Grant Files - Columbia University College of Physicians and Surgeons - Turino, 1982 (Box 34, Folder 12)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - Grant Files - Duke University - Adams, 1988 (Box 34, Folder 13-14)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - Grant Files - Duke University - Robertson, 1983-1988 (Box 34, Folder 15)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - Grant Files - Duke University - Robertson, 1981-1982 (Box 35, Folder 1-2)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - Grant Files - Eleanor Roosevelt Institute - Puck, 1979-1988 (Box 35, Folder 3-6)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - Grant Files - Harvard Medical School, 1980-1983 (Box 35, Folder 7-8)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - Grant Files - Harvard Medical School - Barger, 1978-1988 (Box 35, Folder 9-10)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - Grant Files - Jackson Laboratory - Sanford, 1982-1985 (Box 35, Folder 11)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - Grant Files - John Hopkins - Ross, 1983-1984 (Box 35, Folder 12)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - Grant Files - La Jolla Cancer Research Foundation - Fishman, 1978 (Box 35, Folder 13)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - Grant Files - Life Sciences Research Foundation, 1981-1985 (Box 35, Folder 14)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - Grant Files - Louisiana State University, 1983-1986 (Box 35, Folder 15-17)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - Grant Files - Louisiana State University, 1983-1986 (Box 36, Folder 1)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - Grant Files - MIT - Wiesner, 1978-1982 (Box 36, Folder 2)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - Grant Files - Medical College of Pennsylvania - Cooper, 1979-1986 (Box 36, Folder 3-4)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - Grant Files - Medical College of Pennsylvania - Dempsey, 1987-1988 (Box 36, Folder 5)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - Grant Files - Medical College of Pennsylvania - Taylor, 1987 (Box 36, Folder 6)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - Grant Files - Memorial Sloan-Kettering Cancer Center (MSKCC), 1979 (Box 36, Folder 7-8)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - Grant Files - NYU Medical Center - Joseph Post, 1971-1984 (Box 36, Folder 9)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - Grant Files - Penn State - Vesell, 1986 (Box 36, Folder 10)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - Grant Files - Purdue - Arnott, 1981-1984 (Box 36, Folder 11)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - Grant Files - Rockefeller University, 1979-1988 (Box 36, Folder 12-13)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - Grant Files - Salk Institute - Frederic de Hoffman, 1983-1986 (Box 36, Folder 14)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - Grant Files - Sidney Farber Center Institute, 1980-1983 (Box 36, Folder 15-17)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - Grant Files - Southwest Foundation for Research, University of Texas Health Science Center (Box 37, Folder 1-6)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - Grant Files - SRI International - Rosenman, 1986 (Box 37, Folder 7)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - Grant Files - Stanford - Dr. Van Tamelen, 1978 (Box 37, Folder 8)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - Grant Files - Trudeau Institute, 1980-1987 (Box 37, Folder 9-12)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - Grant Files - Tulane University, 1987-1988 (Box 37, Folder 13)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - Grant Files - UCLA - Cline, 1979-1986 (Box 37, Folder 14)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - Grant Files - University of California, San Diego - Moser, 1978-1988 (Box 37, Folder 15-18)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - Grant Files - University of California, San Francisco - Goetzl, Nadel, 1983-1986 (Box 38, Folder 1-3)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - Grant Files - University of California, San Francisco - Julius Krevans, 1979-1983 (Box 38, Folder 4)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - Grant Files - University of California, San Francisco - Prusiner, 1980-1989 (Box 38, Folder 5-15)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - Grant Files - University of California, San Francisco - Prusiner, 1980-1987 (Box 39, Folder 1-2)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - Grant Files - University of Colorado - Pierce, 1976-1988 (Box 39, Folder 3-7)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - Grant Files - University of Connecticut - Herbette, 1988 (Box 39, Folder 8)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - Grant Files - University of Michigan - Julius, 1988 (Box 39, Folder 9)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - Grant Files - University of Mississippi - Klyyken, 1987 (Box 39, Folder 10)
- R. J. Reynolds - Biomedical Research Program - Grant Files - University of North Carolina-Chapel Hill - Sancar, 1987 (Box 39, Folder 11)